Guide to the Anson Phelps Stokes Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Memorabilia and Photos, 1761-(1874-1958); PART I. IV; 7 linear feet (17 boxes)
  - Parents and Older Relatives of Anson Phelps Stokes
    - Caroline (1854-1909) and Olivia Phelps Stokes (1847-1927), aunts of APS
      - Clippings and a letter re: the philanthropies of the Stokes sisters, 1879-1911 (Box 197, Folder 72)
      - Programs and a pamphlet concerning their philanthropic interest in Tuskegee Institute, 1889, 1893 (Box 197, Folder 73)
      - Bill from Houghton & Company to Olivia E. Phelps Stokes for the printing costs of "Memories of James Stokes", 1893 January 19 (Box 197, Folder 74)
      - Extracts from "The Story of Caroline Phelps Stokes" by Olivia E. Phelps Stokes, undated (Box 197, Folder 75)
      - Obituary notice for Olivia E. Phelps Stokes, 1927 December 15 (Box 197, Folder 76)
    - The Phelps Stokes Family
      - Clippings, pamphlets, excerpts from town records relating the Phelps Stokes family to Ansonia, Connecticut, 1897-1941 (Box 197, Folder 77)
      - Correspondence, clippings, pamphlets and minutes indicating the family's interest in the Y.M.C.A. and the Y.W.C.A., 1870-1945 (Box 197, Folder 78)
  - Anson Phelps Stokes
    - Memorabilia, 1874-1892 August (Box 198, Folder 79-82)
    - Memorabilia, 1892 September - 1895 (Box 199, Folder 83)
    - Yale scrapbook, 1892-1896 (Box 199, Folder 84)
    - Yale scrapbook, 1894-1896 (Box 200, Folder 85)
    - Memorabilia, 1896-1900 (Box 200, Folder 86-90)
    - Memorabilia, 1901-1904 (Box 201, Folder 91-97)
    - Memorabilia, 1905-1913 (Box 202, Folder 98-106)
    - Memorabilia, 1914-1926 (Box 203, Folder 107-115)
    - Memorabilia, 1927-1935 (Box 204, Folder 116-124)
    - Memorabilia, 1936-1944 (Box 205, Folder 125-133)
    - Memorabilia, 1945-1951 (Box 206, Folder 134-142)
    - Memorabilia, 1952-1957, undated (Box 207, Folder 143-147)
    - A Chinese scroll, undated (Box 207, Folder 148)
    - Memoirs of Anson Phelps Stokes for his children and grandchildren (fragments), Circa 1954 (Box 207, Folder 149)
    - Biographical information on Anson Phelps Stokes, 1874-1958 (Box 207, Folder 150)
    - Bound scrapbooks, compiled by APS
      - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, Volume I, 1905 - 1921 (Box 208, Folder 151)
      - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, Volume II, 1921 - 1930 (Box 208, Folder 152)
      - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Reports, Volume III, 1931-1934 (Box 209, Folder 153)
      - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Reports, Volume IV (with index for Vols. I-IV), 1934-1936 (Box 210, Folder 154)
      - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Papers, Volume V, 1937-1942 (Box 210, Folder 155)
  - Photographs
    - Photos of APS: Childhood, 1874 - circa 1884 (Box 211, Folder 156)
    - Photos of APS: Adolescence, Circa 1884 - 1892 (Box 211, Folder 157)
    - Photos of APS: Years at Yale, 1892 - 1921 (Box 211, Folder 158)
    - Photos of APS: Years at Washington Cathedral, 1924-1939 (Box 211, Folder 159)
    - Photos of APS: Passport photos of APS and Carol M. Phelps Stokes, Circa 1930 (Box 211, Folder 160)
    - Photos of APS: Later years, 1940-1958 (Box 211, Folder 161)
    - Photos of APS: Reproduction of a portrait, Circa 1946 (Box 211, Folder 162)
    - Family photos of APS: With his father and son, 1905 (Box 211, Folder 163)
    - Family photos of APS: With his parents, his wife, and son Anson, Circa 1905 (Box 211, Folder 164)
    - Family photos of APS: With his wife and children, 1907, 1908, 1913 (Box 211, Folder 165)
    - Family photos of APS: With his wife and children, Circa 1929 (Box 211, Folder 166)
    - Group photos of APS: St. Paul's School, Concord, N.H., Circa 1890 (Box 211, Folder 167)
    - Group photos of APS: World's Students in Federation, Circa 1898-1899 (Box 211, Folder 168)
    - Group photos of APS: Yale, Circa 1896 (Box 211, Folder 169)
    - Group photos of APS: St. Paul's Church, New Haven, 1903 (Box 211, Folder 170)
    - Photo of the General Education Board in 1915
      See: Part I, box 226
    - Group photos of APS: With Sir Esme Howard and Sir Gordon Guggisberg, Circa 1927 (Box 211, Folder 171)
    - Group photos of APS: Laying the cornerstone at Langston Terrace housing development in Washington, D.C., 1937 (Box 211, Folder 172)
    - Group photos of APS: Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1945, 1952 (Box 211, Folder 173)
    - Group photos of APS: 55th Anniversary of the Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, 1951 June (Box 211, Folder 174)
    - Group photos of APS: 55th Reunion of the Class of 1896, Yale University, 1951 (Box 211, Folder 175)
    - Caricatures of APS, undated (Box 211, Folder 176)
    - Photos from travels in the Far East, 1897, undated (Box 211, Folder 177)
    - Photo of room at Yale, photo of Secretary's table (?), undated (Box 211, Folder 178)
    - Photos of interior and exterior of the Pierpont-Stokes house on Elm Street in New Haven
      See: Part I, box 227
    - Phelps-Stokes family photos, undated (Box 211, Folder 179-181)
    - Photo of the conference room in the Amerika-Institut in Berlin, undated (Box 211, Folder 182)
    - Photos, miscellaneous, undated (Box 211, Folder 183)
    - Photos of Yale-in-China
      See: Part I, box 193, folders 409-419
- Financial and Property Records, 1804-(1910-1958); PART I. V; 3.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
  The financial and property records are divided into four sub-sections: Financial and Property Records of Anson Phelps Stokes, Settlements of Family Estates, Phelps Stokes Estates, and Phelps Stokes Corporation.
  "Financial and Property Records" are arranged alphabetically by folder title. In "Settlements of Family Estates," material is arranged by the name of the deceased family member. The order of the names is chronological according to the year of birth. "Phelps Stokes Estates" and "Phelps Stokes Corporation" refer to the corporate form of the family's investments and securities. These sub-sections consist of Anson Phelps Stokes's copies of the corporation's reports and records, arranged chronologically. ( Note: Phelps Stokes Estates, Inc., which later became the Phelps Stokes Corporation, should not be confused with the Phelps-Stokes Fund, established by the will of Caroline Phelps Stokes to support educational and housing projects in Africa and in the United States.)
  - Financial and Property Records of Anson Phelps Stokes
    - Automobiles, related papers and finances, 1928-1958 (Box 212, Folder 1-2)
    - Bills and receipts for Chinese purchases, 1920 (Box 212, Folder 3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1920-1958 (Box 212, Folder 4-7)
    - Brook Farm, list of supplies and expenses for the year, 1911 (Box 212, Folder 8)
    - Brook Farm guernseys, catalogue of the dispersal sale, 1922 September 22 (Box 212, Folder 9)
    - Brook Farm herd, papers and records (Box 212, Folder 10)
    - Brook Farm agreement with Leslie K. Cheney, 1947 (Box 212, Folder 11)
    - Budget estimates, 1930-1948 (Box 212, Folder 12-13)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1944 (Box 212, Folder 14)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1944 (Box 212, Folder 15)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1945 (Box 212, Folder 16)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1945 (Box 212, Folder 17)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1946 (Box 213, Folder 18)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York, 1946 January-December (Box 213, Folder 19-20)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1947 (Box 213, Folder 21)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1947 (Box 213, Folder 22)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1948 (Box 213, Folder 23)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, joint account with Carol M.P. Stokes, Lenox, 1948 December (Box 213, Folder 24)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1948 (Box 214, Folder 25)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1949 (Box 214, Folder 26)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1949 (Box 214, Folder 27)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1951 (Box 214, Folder 28)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1951 (Box 214, Folder 29)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1952 (Box 215, Folder 30)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1952 (Box 215, Folder 31)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1953 (Box 215, Folder 32)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1953 (Box 215, Folder 33)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1954 (Box 216, Folder 34)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, New York (incomplete), 1954 (Box 216, Folder 35)
    - Cancelled checks and bank statements, Lenox (incomplete), 1955 (Box 216, Folder 36)
    - Check stub books, Lenox (incomplete), 1945 April - 1954 May (Box 216, Folder 37)
    - Check stub books, New York, 1944 July - 1946 February (Box 216, Folder 38)
    - Check stub books, New York (incomplete), 1948, 1949 January 1 - 1950 April (Box 217, Folder 39)
    - Check stub books, New York, 1952 October - 1955 October (Box 217, Folder 40-41)
    - Collection of American bookplates, memoranda and correspondence about, 1940 (Box 217, Folder 42)
    - Inventories of furnishings, 1911, 1942-1957, n.d (Box 217, Folder 43)
    - Landlord's petition for adjustment of rent, registration for the Office of Price Administration, and rental information for Honeymoon Cottage, 1941-1951, undated (Box 217, Folder 44)
    - Lease of Stockbridge property, 1936 (Box 217, Folder 45)
    - Lease for Brook Lodge, 1942 (Box 217, Folder 46)
    - Leases for Lake Cottage, 1942-1947 (Box 217, Folder 47)
    - Leases for Chanticleer Cottage, 1949, 1955 (Box 217, Folder 48)
    - Lease for Silver Run Cottage; copy of Stokes's advertisement, 1952 (Box 217, Folder 49)
    - Lenox National Bank, agent checking account of Rosalie Malone, 1932, undated (Box 217, Folder 50)
    - Liberty bonds, copy of an explanatory letter from APS to his children, 1930 October 23 (Box 217, Folder 51)
    - Loans outstanding, 1937 November (Box 217, Folder 52)
    - Membership cards, 1920-1940 (Box 217, Folder 53)
    - Memorandum re: disposition of "History of Universities" research materials, 1925 November 4 (Box 217, Folder 54)
    - Taxes, 1910, 1913, 1914, 1920-1921, 1924-1941 (Box 218, Folder 55-65)
    - Last will and testament, cancelled in 1948, with TLS of Samuel Thorne to APS, 1929 July (Box 218, Folder 65)
  - Settlements of Family Estates
    - Anson Greene Phelps (1781-1853): Record book with inventory of the estate, bill of sale for furniture, 1804, 1854-1862 (Box 219, Folder 66)
    - Anson Greene Phelps (1781-1853): Last will and testament (printed copy), 1852 March 24 (Box 219, Folder 67)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps (1802-1888): Lawsuits against executors of the last will and testament of I.N. Phelps, 1914, 1922 (Box 219, Folder 68)
    - James Stokes (1804-1881): Account in the Daily Register of New York of a suit by Dora Stokes Dale re: estate of James Stokes, 1882 May 10 (Box 219, Folder 69)
    - James Stokes (1804-1881): Map, memorandum, copies of power of attorney and correspondence re: Michigan land of James Stokes, 1937, 1938 (Box 219, Folder 70)
    - Caroline Phelps Stokes (1812-1881): Last will and testament (printed copy), 1880 (Box 219, Folder 71)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes (1838-1913): Last will and testament (typed copy) (Box 219, Folder 72)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes (1838-1913): Inventory of the estate, appraisal of paintings, books, and bronzes (Box 219, Folder 73)
    - James Boulter Stokes, Jr. (1842-1918): TLS of John C. Clark to Helen Phelps Stokes re: will of James Stokes, Jr., 1918 October 18 (Box 219, Folder 74)
    - Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes (1846-1930): Inventory and appraisal of the estate (Box 219, Folder 75)
    - Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes (1846-1930): Correspondence of APS with his brothers Newton and Harold, James W. McCulloch, and others about the estate of H.L.P.S., 1930-1932 (Box 219, Folder 76)
    - Olivia Egleston Phelps Stokes (1847-1927): Documents of the estate, 1927-1929 (Box 219, Folder 77)
    - Elizabeth Cossitt Stokes (?): Second supplemental citation of the Surrogate's Court of the County of New York in re settlement of her will, 1943 May 3 (Box 219, Folder 78)
    - Elizabeth Cossitt Stokes (?): Power of attorney from APS to Clarence B. Mitchell in re settlement of the will of E.C.S., 1950 June 5 (Box 219, Folder 79)
    - Edith Minturn Phelps Stokes (18 ?-1937): Release of claim to the estate signed by APS, 1940 October 16 (Box 219, Folder 80)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes (1867-1945): TLS of APS to his brothers and sisters re: solution of I.N. Phelps Stokes's financial difficulties, 1939 September 29 (Box 219, Folder 81)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes (1867-1945): Copy of his last will and testament, 1939 May 3 (Box 219, Folder 82)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes (1867-1945): Correspondence re: estate of I.N.P.S., Edwin K. Merrill and APS, executors, 1939 May - 1948 December (Box 219, Folder 83)
    - Sarah M.P. Stokes Halkett (1869-1943): Copy of receipt signed by APS for items received in settlement of the estate of his sister, 1943 October 19 (Box 219, Folder 84)
    - Helen Olivia Phelps Stokes (1870-1946): TLS of the Fifth Avenue Bank of New York to APS, 1946 November 14 (Box 219, Folder 85)
    - Helen Olivia Phelps Stokes (1870-1946): Memorandum re: Stokes Properties, Inc., held by the estate of Helen Phelps Stokes, 1949 January 13 (Box 219, Folder 86)
    - Elizabeth Stokes Terrien (? -1950): Carbon copy of TLS of APS to his brothers and sisters re: her estate, 1950 June 5 (Box 219, Folder 87)
    - Mitchell real estate, 1912 - 1920 (Box 219, Folder 88)
    - Correspondence re: family estates
      See: Stewart and Shearer, Part I, box 44, folder 737
  - Phelps Stokes Estates
    - General manager's report, 1924 March (Box 219, Folder 89)
    - General manager's reports for directors' meetings, 1924 June 28, November 29, December 27 (Box 219, Folder 90)
    - Auditor's report, 1924 December 31 (Box 219, Folder 91)
    - Estimates of costs and revenue of the Woodbridge Building, Circa 1924 - 1925 (Box 220, Folder 92)
    - General manager's reports for directors' meetings, 1925 January 31, March 28 (Box 220, Folder 93)
    - Minutes of meetings of the directors of the Phelps Stokes Estates, 1925 February 28 (Box 220, Folder 94)
    - General manager's reports for directors' meetings, 1925 May 29, August 1, August 29 (Box 220, Folder 95)
    - Minutes of meetings of the directors, 1926 February 27; June 30 (Box 220, Folder 96)
    - Business transactions and earnings from 1914 to 1926 Apr, 1926 April 21 (Box 220, Folder 97)
    - General manager's report, 1926 June (Box 220, Folder 98)
  - Phelps Stokes Corporation
    - By-laws of the corporation, (1927) (Box 220, Folder 99)
    - General manager's report, 1927 May 3 (Box 220, Folder 100)
    - Annual reports, 1927, 1928, 1929-1932, 1934 (Box 220, Folder 101-102)
    - General manager's reports for directors' meetings, 1930 January 13, April 14, 1931 January 13 (Box 220, Folder 103)
    - General manager's reports for executive committee and directors, 1933-1935 (Box 220, Folder 104-105)
    - Family interests, 1935-1936 (Box 220, Folder 106-107)
    - General manager's reports for executive committee and directors, 1936 (Box 220, Folder 108)
    - General manager's reports, 1937-1938 (Box 220, Folder 109)
    - Annual reports, 1936, 1938, 1939-1941, 1943-1945 (Box 220, Folder 110-111)
    - Minutes of meetings of stockholders, 1945 January 1; 1950 March 21 (Box 220, Folder 112)
    - Financial reports for executive committee and directors, 1945-1947, 1949 (Box 220, Folder 113-115)
    - Annual report, 1948 (Box 220, Folder 116)
- Stokes Family Papers, 1834-1960; PART I. VI; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Part I, Series VI, Stokes Family Papers, contains correspondence, writings, and miscellaneous papers of Stokes family members other than Anson Phelps Stokes. The series is divided into "Family Papers, General" and "Family Papers, Individual."
  The general family papers consist of two boxes of Phelps Stokes correspondence arranged chronologically from 1834 to 1960. Included are copies of the Phelps Stokes Family News Sheet from the 1930's to 1960.
  The individual family papers includes material from:
  Anson Phelps Stokes (1838-1913)
  Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes (1846-1930)
  Olivia Egleston Phelps Stokes (1847-1927)
  Caroline Phelps Stokes (1854-1909)
  James Graham Phelps Stokes (1872-1819)
  Anson Phelps Stokes III (1905-)
  Issac Newton Phelps Stokes (1906-)
  Helen Olivia Phelps Stokes (1870-1946)
  Note: Additional correspondence of the individuals listed above may be found in the general Phelps Stokes correspondence, boxes 221 and 222.
  Note: For Phelps Stokes family history, see: Part I, Series IV
  - Family Papers, General
    - Phelps Stokes correspondence, 1834-1912 June (Box 221, Folder 1-15)
    - Phelps Stokes correspondence, 1912 July - 1960, undated (Box 222, Folder 16-28)
    - Phelps Stokes Family News Sheet, contributions from Anson Phelps Stokes, 1931-1939, undated (Box 222, Folder 29)
    - Phelps Stokes Family News Sheet, 1943 Mar 15; 1949 Jun 15; 1954 Jan 15; 1956 Jan 15; Apr 15; Jul 15; Oct 15; 1957 Jan 15; Apr 15; Jul 15; Nov 15; 1958 Jan 15; Apr 15; Jul 15; 1959 Apr 15; Jul 15; 1960 Jul 15 (Box 222, Folder 30-34)
  - Family Papers, Individual
    - Anson Phelps Stokes (1838-1913)
      - Sympathy letters to Anson Phelps Stokes, Sr., for leg injury and amputation received in 1899, A-B (Box 223, Folder 35)
      - Sympathy letters, C-F (Box 223, Folder 36)
      - Sympathy letters, G-H (Box 223, Folder 37)
      - Sympathy letters, I-L (Box 223, Folder 38)
      - Sympathy letters, M-O (Box 223, Folder 39)
      - Sympathy letters, P-Q (Box 223, Folder 40)
      - Sympathy letters, R (Box 223, Folder 41)
      - Sympathy letters, S (Box 223, Folder 42)
      - Sympathy letters, T-Z (Box 223, Folder 43)
      - Sympathy letters on the death of Anson Phelps Stokes, Sr., 1913 (Box 223, Folder 44-45)
      - Correspondence of Anson Phelps Stokes, Sr., with family and friends
        See: Part I, box 221, folders 1-15 See: Part I, box 222, folders 16-28
    - Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes (1846-1930)
      - Sympathy letters on the death of Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes, 1930 (Box 223, Folder 46)
      - Correspondence of Helen L. Phelps Stokes
        See: Part I, box 221, folder 1-15 See: Part I, box 222, folder 16-28
    - Olivia Egleston Phelps Stokes (1847-1927) and Caroline Phelps Stokes (1854-1909)
      - Letters re: the philanthropic interests of the Stokes sisters, 1880-1909 (Box 223, Folder 47-48)
      - Letters re: the philanthropic interests of Olivia E. Phelps Stokes, 1910-1927, undated (Box 223, Folder 49-50)
      - Letters from Susan Warner, 1883-1884 (Box 224, Folder 51)
      - Letters from Anna B. Warner, 1885-1913 (Box 224, Folder 52-54)
      - Clippings of Booker T. Washington, 1895, 1898 (Box 224, Folder 55)
      - Letters from Booker T. Washington, 1896-1915 (Box 224, Folder 56-57)
      - TLS from G. Lake Imes to Olivia E.P. Stokes, 1916 March 28 (Box 224, Folder 58)
      - Letters from Margaret I. Washington (Mrs. Booker T. Washington) to O.E.P.S., 1916-1922 (Box 224, Folder 59)
      - ALS from Georgia Washington to O.E.P.S., 1928 June 6 (Box 224, Folder 60)
      - Student's outline memoranda of O.E.P.S., 1891-1892 (Box 224, Folder 61)
      - Additional correspondence.
    - James Graham Phelps Stokes (1872-1960)
      - Unofficial war activities of Captain J.G. Phelps Stokes, CA-ORC, 1922 (Box 224, Folder 62)
      - "The One Lord of East and West," article, 1956 October (Box 224, Folder 63)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes III (1905-) and Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes (1906- )
      - Typed copy of the journal of Anson Phelps Stokes III during his travels in India and the Middle East, 1930 March 23 - April 17 (Box 224, Folder 64)
      - "Marching with Gandhi," quotation from a personal letter of Newton Phelps Stokes to his parents, (1930) (Box 224, Folder 65)
      - Newspaper clippings of the travels of Anson and Newton Phelps Stokes, (1930) (Box 224, Folder 66)
    - Helen Olivia Phelps Stokes (1870-1946)
      - Correspondence
        - Baldwin, Roger N., 1917-1919 (Box 225, Folder 67)
        - Burt, Roy E., 1937 November 26 (Box 225, Folder 68)
        - DeSilver, Albert, 1919 May 16; 1920 May 26 (Box 225, Folder 69)
        - Eastman, Max, 1912 November 25 (Box 225, Folder 70)
        - Eliot, Charles W., 1916 June 7 (Box 225, Folder 71)
        - Frost, William G. and Eleanor M., 1928 October 3 (Box 225, Folder 72)
        - Gannett, W. Wyllys, 1893 April 20 (Box 225, Folder 73)
        - Greatorex, Kate, 1928 July 2 (Box 225, Folder 74)
        - Kendall, Sargeant and M., 1911 December 22; December 27; undated (Box 225, Folder 75)
        - Laidler, Harry W., 1937 July 14 (Box 225, Folder 76)
        - Lowell, Josephine Shaw, 1904 August 10 (Box 225, Folder 77)
        - Percy, Lord Eustace, 1913 May 6; November 23 (Box 225, Folder 78)
        - Rousseau, Elmina, 1913 May 13 (Box 225, Folder 79)
        - Scudder, Vida D., 1913 December 4; 1919 February 8 (Box 225, Folder 80)
        - Simkhovitch, Mary K., 1929 February 20 (Box 225, Folder 81)
        - Spargo, John, 1910 November 21 (Box 225, Folder 82)
        - Stokes, Rose Pastor, 1908 July 29; 1913 July 21; 1916 August 3 (Box 225, Folder 83)
        - Thomas, Norman, 1936 January 9 (Box 225, Folder 84)
        - Trudeau, Edward L., 1907 August 11, December 25, undated (Box 225, Folder 85)
        - Wald, Lillian D. TLS to Helen Phelps Stokes, 1917 March 28 (Box 225, Folder 86)
        - TLS from J.P. Tumulty, Secretary to the President of the United States, to Lillian Wald, 1917 March 29
        - Ward, William Hayes, 1910 December 6 (Box 225, Folder 87)
        - Unidentified, 1919 June 9 (Box 225, Folder 88)
        - Additional correspondence of Helen Phelps Stokes
      - Outline and reports
        - Outlook on life, Circa 1915 (Box 225, Folder 89)
        - Report of Helen Phelps Stokes and Mary R. Sanford to the Consumers' League of New York, 1917 July 17 - August 18 (Box 225, Folder 90)
        - Reports of the Employment Committee of the Mayor's Committee of Women on National Defense, 1917 August 10, August 29 (Box 225, Folder 91)
        - National Civil Liberties Bureau
          - Minutes, memoranda, bulletins, and reports, 1917 December - 1919 December (Box 225, Folder 92-95)
          - Publications, 1918-1919, undated (Box 225, Folder 96-97)
        - American Civil Liberties Union
          - Minutes, memoranda, bulletins and reports, 1920 May - Oct; 1921; undated (Box 225, Folder 98-99)
          - Publications, 1920-1923, undated (Box 225, Folder 100)
- Oversize Materials, PART I
  - Individual and group photographs of Anson Phelps Stokes and the Stokes family, certificates, diplomas, and miscellaneous documents of Anson Phelps Stokes and others (Box 226)
  - Photographs of the interior and the exterior of the Pierpont-Stokes House, now the Faculty Club, Elm Street, New Haven (Box 227)
- Correspondence, 1893-1957 (primarily 1896-1923, 1950-1957); PART II. I; 26 linear feet (62 boxes)
  Part II, Series I, Correspondence, is divided into four sections:
  A. General Correspondence, 1893-1923
  B. Letterpress Books, 1900-1921
  C. General Correspondence, 1950-1957
  D. Family Correspondence, 1897-1957